A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Policy Office, Records, 2002-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Library of Virginia
- III. Legislative Files, 2006-2009 (accession 44701)., Extent: 33.60 cubic feet (96 boxes). (Box 49-141, 170-172)
  - 2008 Regular Session
    - House of Delegates
      - HB 837 (08) Dam break inundation zones; localities with authority to address development (Box 104, Folder 16)
      - HB 838 (08) Criminal Justice Services Board; establishment of Executive Committee (Box 104, Folder 17)
      - HB 839 (08) Interoperability Executive Committee; established, report (Box 104, Folder 18)
      - HB 840 (08) Capitol Police, Division of; powers and duties (Box 104, Folder 19)
      - HB 841 (08) Capitol District; established as geographic seat of government (Box 104, Folder 20)
      - HB 842 (08) Concealed weapons; exempts retired Capitol Police officers from permit requirements (Box 104, Folder 21)
      - HB 844 (08) Sex Offender and Crimes Against Minors Registry; use of data by SAVIN (Box 104, Folder 22)
      - HB 845 (08) Charter; City of Winchester (Box 104, Folder 23)
      - HB 847 (08) Charter; City of Winchester (Box 104, Folder 24)
      - HB 849 (08) Land preservation tax credit; taxpayer to give consent when tax credit, etc. has been transferred (Box 104, Folder 25)
      - HB 850 (08) Foster care; require code of ethics agreement signed by head of every foster home, etc. (Box 104, Folder 26)
      - HB 853 (08) Service dogs; persons training entitled to be accompanied thereby in public places (Box 104, Folder 27)
      - HB 854 (08) Freedom of Information Act; local public bodies may meet by electronic communication (Box 104, Folder 28)
      - HB 861 (08) Caregivers Grant Program; physician assistant or nurse practitioner to certify (Box 104, Folder 29)
      - HB 866 (08) Criminal Justice Services, Department of; limitation on licensure for bail bondsmen (Box 104, Folder 30)
      - HB 867 (08) Public Procurement Act; regional industrial facility authorities to enter into certain contracts (Box 104, Folder 31)
      - HB 869 (08) Personal property tax; uncollected balances added to delinquent list maintained by Treasurer (Box 104, Folder 32)
      - HB 870 (08) Mineral Resources, Division of; name changed to Division of Geology and Mineral Resources (Box 104, Folder 33)
      - HB 871 (08) Marriage and family programs; Department of Social Services to establish (Box 104, Folder 34)
      - HB 873 (08) Concealed handgun permits; proof of competency with handgun (Box 104, Folder 35)
      - HB 875 (08) Handbills, etc.; distribution in Spotsylvania County and City of Richmond (Box 104, Folder 36)
      - HB 877 (08) Community development authority board; City of Richmond appoint seven members (Box 104, Folder 37)
      - HB 879 (08) Affordable dwelling unit ordinances; may establish requirement that prices for resale be controlled (Box 104, Folder 38)
      - HB 881 (08) Employment Commission; authorizes final orders to be recorded and satisfied as orders (Box 104, Folder 39)
      - HB 882 (08) Administrative orders; collection of interest (Box 104, Folder 40)
      - HB 883 (08) Affordable housing; permitting certain densities in plan in City of Charlottesville (Box 104, Folder 41)
      - HB 885 (08) Bus engine idling; allows all counties, cities, and towns power to adopt ordinances limiting (Box 104, Folder 42)
      - HB 886 (08) Bear hunting; clarifies time of day during hound training season (Box 104, Folder 43)
      - HB 889 (08) Learner's permits; certification statement required for persons under age 18 (Box 104, Folder 44)
      - HB 890 (08) Emergency vehicles; flashing warning lights (Box 104, Folder 45)
      - HB 900 (08) Value engineering; submission thereof to report to Division of Engineering and Buildings (Box 105, Folder 1)
      - HB 902 (08) Sex Offender and Crimes Against Minors Registry Act; registration procedures (Box 105, Folder 2)
      - HB 903 (08) Magistrates; reforms system by transferring appointment and supervisory responsibilities (Box 105, Folder 3)
      - HB 908 (08) Alcoholic beverage control; operation of government stores on Sunday (Box 105, Folder 4)
      - HB 912 (08) Income tax, state; conformity of system with Internal Revenue Code (Box 105, Folder 5)
      - HB 914 (08) Liability, fire, and motor vehicle insurance policies; establishes exceptions to prohibitions (Box 105, Folder 6)
      - HB 915 (08) Credit Counseling Act; removes two factors that SCC is required to use when setting fees (Box 105, Folder 7)
      - HB 917 (08) Clerk's office; preservation of papers (Box 105, Folder 8)
      - HB 918 (08) Corporations and professional limited liability companies; conforms provisions that govern mergers (Box 105, Folder 9)
      - HB 922 (08) Registration fees; increase for fire fighting and emergency medical services vehicles (Box 105, Folder 10)
      - HB 925 (08) Employment Commission; employment stabilization (Box 105, Folder 11)
      - HB 926 (08) Illegal aliens; corporate existence terminated involuntarily for employing (Box 105, Folder 12)
      - HB 931 (08) Methamphetamine; manufacturing, selling, giving, and distributing thereof, penalty (Box 105, Folder 13)
      - HB 933 (08) Triggerman rule; redefinition thereof (Box 105, Folder 14)
      - HB 934 (08) Jail inmates; no parole for those convicted of multiple misdemeanors and sentenced more than 12 month (Box 105, Folder 15)
      - HB 936 (08) Composite index, local; number of students (Box 105, Folder 16)
      - HB 941 (08) Search warrants; allows an affidavit to be delivered by facsimile after it is certified (Box 105, Folder 17)
      - HB 944 (08) Public Procurement Act; procurement of professional services for certain transportation projects (Box 105, Folder 18)
      - HB 945 (08) Court of Appeals; en banc hearings (Box 105, Folder 19)
      - HB 946 (08) Adoption; period of validity of home study (Box 105, Folder 20)
      - HB 949 (08) Slayer statute; insurance company not liable for policies acquired by slayer of decedent (Box 105, Folder 21)
      - HB 951 (08) Uniform Prudent Management of Institutional Funds Act; created (Box 105, Folder 22)
      - HB 952 (08) Insanity plea; time period for notice (Box 105, Folder 23)
      - HB 955 (08) Public-Private Education Facilities and Infrastructure Act of 2002; definition of qualifying projects (Box 105, Folder 24)
      - HB 956 (08) Criminal Injuries Compensation Fund; physical evidence recovery kit examinations reimbursements (Box 105, Folder 25)
      - HB 965 (08) Victims Compensation Fund; amends definition to include stalking victims (Box 105, Folder 26)
      - HB 972 (08) Ford and Pullman grants; ratifies conveyance of certain lands in County of Fairfax (Box 105, Folder 27)
      - HB 978 (08) Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University; Board of Visitors to convey certain property to Virginia Tech Foundation, Inc. (Box 105, Folder 28)
      - HB 979 (08) TAG; eligibility for students attending Edward Via Virginia College of Osteopathic Medicine (Box 105, Folder 29)
      - HB 983 (08) Charter; City of Radford (Box 105, Folder 30)
      - HB 989 (08) University of Virginia; appointment of board of visitors (Box 105, Folder 31)
      - HB 990 (08) Pyramid promotional schemes; definition thereof, penalty (Box 105, Folder 32)
      - HB 991 (08) Development rights; allows Albemarle County to enact an ordinance for severance and transfer (Box 105, Folder 33)
      - HB 995 (08) Unlawful filming of another; guilty of Class 6 felony (Box 105, Folder 34)
      - HB 999 (08) Animals; posting of bond by owners of those abandoned or cruelly treated (Box 105, Folder 35)
      - HB 1000 (08) Community College Education, Foundation for; contribution to be deposited for State residents (Box 105, Folder 36)
      - HB 1003 (08) Nursing workforce information; publication on website (Box 105, Folder 37)
      - HB 1005 (08) Higher educational institutions; notification to parent of mental health treatment for student (Box 105, Folder 38)
      - HB 1007 (08) Fusion Intelligence Center; confidentiality and immunity from service of process (Box 105, Folder 39)
      - HB 1012 (08) Towing; regulations for those seeking tow truck authorization documents and provisional changes (Box 105, Folder 40)
      - HB 1013 (08) Newman Road; designating as State byway in Fairfax County (Box 106, Folder 1)
      - HB 1014 (08) High-occupancy vehicle (HOV) lanes; use by vehicles bearing special fuel vehicle license plates (Box 106, Folder 2)
      - HB 1015 (08) Motor vehicle air conditioners; allows explosive, flammable, or toxic refrigerants (Box 106, Folder 3)
      - HB 1016 (08) Deer; Department of Game and Inland Fisheries to allow killing thereof over bait (Box 106, Folder 4)
      - HB 1017 (08) Telework Promotion and Broadband Assistance, Office of; established, report (Box 106, Folder 5)
      - HB 1018 (08) Telecommuting; definition (Box 106, Folder 6)
      - HB 1021 (08) Telecommuting; establishes goal for state agencies (Box 106, Folder 7)
      - HB 1023 (08) Collection of debts; reciprocal agreement with federal government to include nontax payments (Box 106, Folder 8)
      - HB 1024 (08) Military personnel; extension of deadlines for driver's license renewal, etc. (Box 106, Folder 9)
      - HB 1025 (08) Breast tumor treatment; repeals requirement that patient sign consent form (Box 106, Folder 10)
      - HB 1032 (08) Traffic control measures; financing for application and installation (Box 106, Folder 11)
      - HB 1037 (08) Nonprofit entities; public meeting prior to disposition of assets (Box 106, Folder 12)
      - HB 1040 (08) Health records; providing information after execution of search warrant, etc. (Box 106, Folder 13)
      - HB 1042 (08) Homestead deeds; previous filings (Box 106, Folder 14)
      - HB 1043 (08) Polygraph; no sexual offense victim shall be requested to submit for investigation to proceed (Box 106, Folder 15)
      - HB 1044 (08) Sex Offenders and Crimes Against Minors Registry; registration requirements (Box 106, Folder 16)
      - HB 1056 (08) Charter; City of Falls Church (Box 106, Folder 17)
      - HB 1058 (08) Higher educational institutions; release of educational records (Box 106, Folder 18)
      - HB 1061 (08) Zoning ordinances; may prescribe an appeal period of less than 30 days (Box 106, Folder 19)
      - HB 1062 (08) Absentee ballot and voting; adds women who are pregnant at time of applying to list of eligible (Box 106, Folder 20)
      - HB 1066 (08) Public Procurement Act; methods of procurement (Box 106, Folder 21)
      - HB 1073 (08) Housing and Community Development, Department of; administration of the Private Activity Bonds (Box 106, Folder 22)
      - HB 1075 (08) Alcoholic beverage control; powers and duties of the Alcoholic Beverage Control Board (Box 106, Folder 23)
      - HB 1077 (08) Real Estate Time Share Act; obligation for fees and limitation on actions (Box 106, Folder 24)
      - HB 1078 (08) Vested rights and nonconforming uses; changes to provisions (Box 106, Folder 25)
      - HB 1079 (08) Zoning, Board of; structure permitted by variance may be expanded under certain conditions (Box 106, Folder 26)
      - HB 1084 (08) Zoning; approval of certain proffered conditions (Box 106, Folder 27)
      - HB 1086 (08) Zoning appeals; written notice of zoning violation (Box 106, Folder 28)
      - HB 1089 (08) Toxic substances; removes requirement Board of Health report to General Assembly biennially (Box 106, Folder 29)
      - HB 1098 (08) Wet Settlement Act; adds to definition of settlement (Box 106, Folder 30)
      - HB 1099 (08) Voter registration records; access to date of birth information (Box 106, Folder 31)
      - HB 1100 (08) Human immunodeficiency virus; informed consent for testing (Box 106, Folder 32)
      - HB 1106 (08) Circuit court clerks; clarifies issues regarding electronic filing and recording of land records, etc. (Box 106, Folder 33)
      - HB 1107 (08) Single-family dwellings; fines for zoning violations related to overcrowding (Box 106, Folder 34)
      - HB 1114 (08) Real Estate Board; real estate firm licenses (Box 106, Folder 35)
      - HB 1115 (08) Forest protection; increases annual amount a locality pays to State Forester therefor (Box 106, Folder 36)
      - HB 1116 (08) Environmental impact reports; required for any major state construction project over $500,000 (Box 106, Folder 37)
      - HB 1117 (08) Alcoholic beverage control; suspension and revocation of licenses if meeting place of street gang (Box 106, Folder 38)
      - HB 1121 (08) Weights and measures; permissible to possess for commercial purposes (Box 106, Folder 39)
      - HB 1123 (08) Real estate and personal property taxes; applied to property of public service corporations, etc. (Box 106, Folder 40)
      - HB 1124 (08) Virginia Commonwealth University; management agreement with State (Box 106, Folder 41)
      - HB 1127 (08) Campaign finance disclosure; required special reports for certain large contributions (Box 107, Folder 1)
      - HB 1128 (08) Pharmacists; continuing education requirements (Box 107, Folder 2)
      - HB 1129 (08) Pharmacy, Board of; expiration of licenses (Box 107, Folder 3)
      - HB 1131 (08) Children's Ombudsman, Office of; created, report (Box 107, Folder 4)
      - HB 1132 (08) Wine and beer; City of Roanoke can obtain retail on-premises licenses for outdoor amphitheaters (Box 107, Folder 5)
      - HB 1133 (08) Deed of trust or mortgage; reduces time in which one may enforce (Box 107, Folder 6)
      - HB 1135 (08) Public schools; student's voluntary expression of a religious viewpoint (Box 107, Folder 7)
      - HB 1140 (08) Tolls; State Corporation Commission authority to approve or revise rates charged (Box 107, Folder 8)
      - HB 1141 (08) Foster care; independent living services (Box 107, Folder 9)
      - HB 1142 (08) Recreational Facilities Authority; delays reversion of title to real property (Box 107, Folder 10)
      - HB 1143 (08) Foster care; visitation rights for siblings (Box 107, Folder 11)
      - HB 1144 (08) Temporary detention order; magistrate may consider recommendation of examining physician, etc. (Box 107, Folder 12)
      - HB 1147 (08) Controlled substances; nonresident pharmacies reporting and approval requirements (Box 107, Folder 13)
      - HB 1149 (08) Recreation facilities; locality may establish trails for all-terrain vehicles, etc. (Box 107, Folder 14)
      - HB 1150 (08) Oil or gas operations; identify in permit application any cemetery located within 100 feet (Box 107, Folder 15)
      - HB 1152 (08) Vehicle window tinting films; exempts rear or rear side windows of ambulances, etc. (Box 107, Folder 16)
      - HB 1160 (08) School bus drivers; removes exclusion from existing provision that prohibits employment of children (Box 107, Folder 17)
      - HB 1166 (08) Onsite treatment works; Board of Health et al., to accept designs from professional engineers (Box 107, Folder 18)
      - HB 1167 (08) Administrative Process Act; public participation guidelines for executive branch agencies (Box 107, Folder 19)
      - HB 1171 (08) Alcoholic mixed beverages; grounds for suspension, etc. of license if obscene material upon premise (Box 107, Folder 20)
      - HB 1172 (08) Charter; Town of Pound (Box 107, Folder 21)
      - HB 1175 (08) Apprentice hunting license; Department of Game and Inland Fisheries to issue (Box 107, Folder 22)
      - HB 1176 (08) Motor vehicle insurance settlement practices; cap on reimbursement for paint and materials (Box 107, Folder 23)
      - HB 1177 (08) Plats; length of validity after all or portion of property recorded (Box 107, Folder 24)
      - HB 1178 (08) Forgery; penalty (Box 107, Folder 25)
      - HB 1179 (08) Assault and battery; admission to bail person committing second or subsequent offense against family (Box 107, Folder 26)
      - HB 1181 (08) Conservators of the peace, special; circuit court judge required to appoint (Box 107, Folder 27)
      - HB 1183 (08) Home instruction of children; requirements (Box 107, Folder 28)
      - HB 1185 (08) Voter registration; cancellation on basis of non-citizenship (Box 107, Folder 29)
      - HB 1186 (08) Incompetent defendants; dismissal of charges when charged with nonviolent misdemeanor (Box 107, Folder 30)
      - HB 1196 (08) Charter; City of Bristol (Box 107, Folder 31)
      - HB 1197 (08) Voter registration; period of time that registration records must be closed before primary election (Box 107, Folder 32)
      - HB 1198 (08) Driver's license, commercial; State law conformance with federal requirements (Box 107, Folder 33)
      - HB 1203 (08) Mental health and substance abuse treatment providers; background checks (Box 107, Folder 34)
      - HB 1205 (08) Diversion center incarceration program; placement of defendant with Department of Corrections (Box 107, Folder 35)
      - HB 1206 (08) Port Authority; police officer to provide security beyond locality where property is located (Box 107, Folder 36)
      - HB 1207 (08) Serious juvenile offenders; those convicted as an adult to gain earned sentence credits (Box 107, Folder 37)
      - HB 1208 (08) Subaqueous lands; Marine Resources Commission to convey parcels thereof (Box 107, Folder 38)
      - HB 1211 (08) Port Authority; establish a trust to offset other postemployment benefits (Box 107, Folder 39)
      - HB 1212 (08) Port Authority; encourages employees thereof to save for retirement (Box 107, Folder 40)
      - HB 1213 (08) HIV/Hepatitis testing; parental consent for minors (Box 107, Folder 41)
      - HB 1214 (08) Trees, state-owned; increases minimum threshold for sales thereof from state forests (Box 108, Folder 1)
      - HB 1215 (08) Charter; City of Emporia (Box 108, Folder 2)
      - HB 1217 (08) Charter; Town of Lawrenceville (Box 108, Folder 3)
      - HB 1218 (08) School buses; prohibits use of wireless telecommunications devices by persons driving (Box 108, Folder 4)
      - HB 1220 (08) Concealed handguns; allows law-enforcement officers on long-term leave to carry without permit (Box 108, Folder 5)
      - HB 1222 (08) Charitable medical events; lack of notice to licensing board (Box 108, Folder 6)
      - HB 1228 (08) Electric utilities; notice of renewable power options (Box 108, Folder 7)
      - HB 1229 (08) Retail Sales and Use Tax; exemptions include WaterSense qualified products (Box 108, Folder 8)
      - HB 1235 (08) Voting equipment; locking and securing after an election (Box 108, Folder 9)
      - HB 1236 (08) Criminal Justice Services, Department of; powers and duties (Box 108, Folder 10)
      - HB 1239 (08) Gourmet shop licenses; licensee shall maintain certain amount of cheeses and gourmet food monthly (Box 108, Folder 11)
      - HB 1240 (08) Manufactured Home Lot Rental Act; access of tenant to cable, satellite, etc. (Box 108, Folder 12)
      - HB 1241 (08) Credit card theft; person who uses, possesses, etc. card of another without cardholder's consent (Box 108, Folder 13)
      - HB 1242 (08) School employees; prohibits employment if subject of a founded case of child abuse and neglect (Box 108, Folder 14)
      - HB 1243 (08) Civil remedial fees; repeals provision for those imposed on certain drivers (Box 108, Folder 15)
      - HB 1245 (08) Driver's license; certain restrictions for first-time applicants failing behind wheel three times (Box 108, Folder 16)
      - HB 1254 (08) Juvenile records; intake officer to report to Bureau of Immigration and Customs if in U.S. illegally (Box 108, Folder 17)
      - HB 1257 (08) Child support enforcement; establishing Intensive Case Monitoring pilot programs (Box 108, Folder 18)
      - HB 1258 (08) Juvenile records; notification of expungement (Box 108, Folder 19)
      - HB 1259 (08) Environmental impact reports; requires county, city, or town to submit report on highway projects (Box 108, Folder 20)
      - HB 1260 (08) Blood donations; allowance of minors age 16 or older to donate (Box 108, Folder 21)
      - HB 1261 (08) Income tax, state; repeals provisions allowing additional withholding exemptions (Box 108, Folder 22)
      - HB 1262 (08) Absentee ballot applications; address given shall be where person is located while confined (Box 108, Folder 23)
      - HB 1265 (08) Health, Department of; payment for medical care services (Box 108, Folder 24)
      - HB 1271 (08) Freedom of Information Act; exemption for local franchises, exception (Box 108, Folder 25)
      - HB 1280 (08) Charitable gaming; regulation under Board and Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services (Box 108, Folder 26)
      - HB 1294 (08) Good Samaritan statute; immunity extends to those providing care at location for screening, etc. (Box 108, Folder 27)
      - HB 1298 (08) Contractors; shall not knowingly employ unauthorized alien (Box 108, Folder 28)
      - HB 1299 (08) Revised Uniform Anatomical Gift Act; resolve situations when conflict between health care directive (Box 108, Folder 29)
      - HB 1302 (08) Incident management; makes several changes to law in order to increase effectiveness and efficiency (Box 108, Folder 30)
      - HB 1305 (08) Birth-Related Neurological Injury Compensation Program; increases annual assessment for physicians (Box 108, Folder 31)
      - HB 1308 (08) Coastal primary sand dunes; authorizes additional localities to adopt ordinance (Box 108, Folder 32)
      - HB 1309 (08) Income tax, state; riparian waterway tax credit (Box 108, Folder 33)
      - HB 1311 (08) Credit reports; authorizes consumer to freeze access thereto (Box 108, Folder 34)
      - HB 1312 (08) Workforce development; Governor's responsibilities (Box 108, Folder 35)
      - HB 1313 (08) Unclaimed property; credit union accounts (Box 108, Folder 36)
      - HB 1317 (08) Subaqueous lands; Marine Resources Commission to convey parcels of previously filled lands (Box 108, Folder 37)
      - HB 1319 (08) Underground transmission lines; pilot program established (Box 108, Folder 38)
      - HB 1320 (08) Public road easements; maintenance of certain roads not abandoned (Box 108, Folder 39)
      - HB 1323 (08) Temporary detention order; magistrates to issue based on recommendation of treating physicians (Box 108, Folder 40)
      - HB 1329 (08) Communication towers, state-owned; wireless broadband service in unserved areas (Box 108, Folder 41)
      - HB 1330 (08) Aerospace Engine Manufacturing Performance Grant Program; created (Box 109, Folder 1)
      - HB 1331 (08) Agriculture and Consumer Services, Department of; recodifying laws pertaining to agriculture, etc. (Box 109, Folder 2)
      - HB 1332 (08) DEQ; authority to issue and enforce permits, etc. related to air and water pollution (Box 109, Folder 3)
      - HB 1334 (08) Conflict of Interests Act, State and Local Government; acceptance of awards (Box 109, Folder 4)
      - HB 1335 (08) Natural Resources Commitment Fund; created (Box 109, Folder 5)
      - HB 1342 (08) Water and sewer charge; adds Isle of Wight County to localities that may attach lien on real estate (Box 109, Folder 6)
      - HB 1345 (08) Parking violations; grants James City County ability to impose civil penalties (Box 109, Folder 7)
      - HB 1354 (08) Substance abuse services; applications for funding (Box 109, Folder 8)
      - HB 1355 (08) Sewage treatment plants; expanded or upgraded facility may limit amount of septage (Box 109, Folder 9)
      - HB 1362 (08) Misuse of public assets; penalty (Box 109, Folder 10)
      - HB 1363 (08) Trademarks and service marks; registration and protection, penalties (Box 109, Folder 11)
      - HB 1367 (08) Freedom of Information Act; exemption for local government investment pool (Box 109, Folder 12)
      - HB 1372 (08) Honey houses; repeals inspection thereof (Box 109, Folder 13)